and finally the issue we want to
consider is what if we broadcast a stale
result let's see what a stale result is
okay so what we have here is a situation
when this divided here is gonna
broadcast its result it's gonna
broadcast that it's a reservation
station for and broadcasting this result
which is the result of the division
between these two numbers but if you
look closely at the rat
none of the registers is currently
renamed to this instruction so how can
this happen well one way of it happening
is that when this instruction was
renamed let's say that F 4 was renamed
to be this result so for a while this
was saying RS 4 but then another
instruction came let's say RS 2 is this
attract and let's say that it was taking
R 4 and this and writing again to the
register for in that case this would not
say RS 2 so simply this instruction no
longer has any of the rat pointing to it
so what's going to happen when we
broadcast this result what's going to
happen is for the filling the
reservation stations it's going to be
done normally pretty much every entry
for every instruction is going to be
matched against the tag here and
wherever we match the tag we're going to
replace it with a value so in this case
we're gonna write instead of this RS 4
here we're gonna get - 0.11 okay that's
the only match so we are done the
question is what happens with the
register file and the rat in that case
in the rat we do nothing why well
because the value from this instruction
will never be used by any of the
instructions that come later the only
reason why we needed the values in the
register file is that after this
broadcast happens all the instructions
that need that value are gonna get it
from the register file so the value had
better been there also all the
instructions that come in after this
instruction are gonna look here to see
what is the newest renamed value of this
result and they're gonna find RS 2 for
example if order for this value however
if this is RS 4 and this is RS 2 that
means that there is a new instruction
that is producing the value for this
register so basically after this
instruction here
has been renamed all the instructions
that come and read f4 should actually
get the new value from you know from
this so this is basically the situation
we had a divided come first for a while
everything the trees f4 should be
getting the value from the divide after
the adhere has renamed f4 to point to it
all the instructions that come after
that are supposed to use this value when
they read our for so so this is entirely
correct behavior so pretty much what we
are doing is when we broadcast this and
capture it here we are giving it to any
of the instructions that sit between
this divide and decide that are actually
using this result but because the add
has already been renamed the
instructions that we are renaming now
and that we are getting results from the
register file those instructions
actually need the value from the add so
they really don't need anything from
from this device so pretty much if the
tag that is being broadcast doesn't
match any of the entries in the rat then
we don't update the rat and we don't
update the register file and it is
perfectly fine because all of the
instructions that possibly need this
value are already reservation stations
when you do quizzes and so on be careful
about this because it is so easy to you
know kind of just make the entry here
point to the register file for example
here you know it would be incorrect to
delete this because it doesn't match
this